

Freelance web developer based in London

Portfolio: thomjamesallen.com GitHub: github.com/tjallen Email: thomwork@gmail.com Mobile: 07747 229 007

Summary

I'm a front-end web developer passionate about building **effective**, **user-friendly web experiences**. Currently focusing on building **modern web app components**, particularly in **React**.

History

(More examples and info for much of the below available on my <u>portfolio site</u> along with various side projects & open-source code on <u>GitHub</u>.)

Freelance Jan 2016–present & 2009–2012

Agency: ASOS.com / ASOS Creates | Clients: PayPal, Hostelworld
Built microsites for ASOS' brand partnerships with PayPal and Hostelworld.
Used Gulp scripts to build from Pug templates into an array of static files, targeting various devices & languages.

Agency: **Dunnhumby** | Client: **Tesco**

Provided QA for Tesco Groceries' XML-based banner ads along with workflow consultancy. Prototyped approvals-oriented web app with Knockout.js and responsive ad components with React.

Agency: StirPR | Client: Felix

Developed responsive HTML emails from provided designs.

Agency: Antidote | Client: Travel Republic

As part of a two developer team I created banner ads with HTML+JS for Travel Republic's summer campaign for a wide variety of destinations and formats. Also created a simple <u>ad viewer</u> to help the agency team quickly review changes & help meet the deadline.

Agency: Antidote | Client: Libratone & Sigma

Created a custom <u>player module</u> for YouTube 360° videos with JavaScript and YouTube's JS API to be used on a landing page, to a strict deadline. Assisted with refactoring colleague's first-draft JS into a revealing module pattern and added BEM and 7-1 code conventions. Created documentation for the handover to back-end devs.

Skills & experience

Front-end fundamentals HTML5, CSS3, Sass, PostCSS, JavaScript to ES6+ with Babel,

JavaScript to ES6+ with Bab TypeScript

Libraries & frameworks

jQuery, React, Vue.js. Bootstrap, Foundation. Electron. GSAP, Anime.js

App state management

Redux, MobX, Flux

Build tools

Webpack, Rollup, Gulp, Grunt

Testing & assertion libs

Mocha, Jest, Tape. Expect, Enzyme. Familiar with TDD, Unit & Snapshot tests, etc

Templating

EJS, Twig, Jade/Pug, Mustache, etc

CMS & back-end

Craft, ExpressionEngine, WordPress, ProcessWire, Grav, Jekyll, etc. Familiar with Nodejs, Express, REST APIs.

Version control

Git (via CLI/terminal)

Development practices

Continuous Integration (w/ TravisCI) Test-driven Development (TDD) Module / Component-based JS development & SemVer Code linting (ESLint etc) & auto-formatting (Prettier etc)

Creativity to make you happy

Designed & developed this responsive Grav-based blog site.

Various clients 2009-12

Designing, building, hosting and maintaining client sites for small businesses.

Open-source & side projects 2016-present

react-simple-range

Released this React component as an NPM package in Sep 2016.

Uses semantic-release & Travis CI for automated releases & package publishing when updates are committed to the master branch. Developed in ES6 and compiled to ES5 with Babel + Webpack.

Worked with open-source contributors to add new features & bugfixes.

countdown-app

A countdown timer app built with React and Electron, featuring web and desktop builds (and a truly original name...)

Part-time 2013-2015

Phosphor Art

Part-time Developer

Built responsive promos and landing pages alongside maintaining, updating and improving existing WordPress site. Created HTML email campaigns & email builder, newsletter signup forms etc. Prototyped a responsive online store page with ExpressionEngine & PayPal's API.

Stuff & Sense

Part-time Developer & consultant

Designed & built the Stuff & Sense company site with a responsive front-end and an ExpressionEngine-based back-end. Provided consultancy services to various clients.

Other work

2011 - Facilities assistant at Google, Buckingham Palace Rd 2008 - Office administrator at Eaux de Vie, Harcourt St (now Marussia Beverages)

About

I'm an efficient, versatile and self-motivated developer.

I've designed and built a number of websites & web apps from the ground up, both solo and with a team. I currently specialise in **front-end development**.

I enjoy learning (and working with) modern, future-facing web technology, and currently prefer using **React** for the view layer of web apps due to its composable, reusable component model, time-efficient development and rich ecosystem.

I'm partial to using **Redux** as a state container, as I believe its consistency & predictability is worth the additional boilerplate.

Education

Self-taught developer.
The Ravensbourne School,
10 GCSEs A* – C

References available on request